<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DroidPile blog</title><link href="http://droidpile.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://droidpile.org/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://droidpile.org/</id><updated>2013-12-23T19:29:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>First post!</title><link href="http://droidpile.org/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-12-23T19:29:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Maikel Wever</name></author><id>tag:droidpile.org,2013-12-23:first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've noticed this blog, then you're probably interested in DroidPile. So what is DroidPile?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DroidPile is an idea I had some time ago, reading over the Mailpile indiegogo page. 
There is a perk there, to hire a developer to create a Android application, but the perk was never funded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February, I have to think of a assignment for school, to keep me busy for half a year, 
and after some consideration, I decided I wanted to create an Android application that's used as a Mailpile client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's what I'll do, create an Android application that's a client for Mailpile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name? Not very original, right? But that's not the point of the name of the application. 
It is supposed to be easy to remember, which I think it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application will provide the following key actions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Composing and sending a new email via the Mailpile instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sending and recieving attachments with emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulling the Inbox from the Mailpile instance (periodically), and show notifications on new messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searching all your emails, using the fast and powerful Mailpile search (so that's server-side)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulling your contacts from your Mailpile instance, and using that for sending emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following ideas may be implemented at a later point in time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merging your Mailpile contact with the phone-global contacts and saving existing entries in Mailpile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backing up your photos and videos on your phone to Mailpile (if Mailpile will support that kind of storage, mockups suggest it will).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development of DroidPile will start in February, and is planned to finish with a 'Minimal Viable Product' half a year later.
The application will most likely be available freely on Google's Play Store, and the source code on GitHub. There will be no ads in the app.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>